<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Ireland. By the Commissioners of the Parliament of the Common-wealth of England for the Affairs of Ireland Whereas many persons, who have been in arms against the Parliament of the Common-wealth of England, and have of late come in upon articles, and submitted to the government of the said Common-wealth, and since their said submission ...</title>
            <author>Ireland. Commissioners of the Common-wealth of England for the Affairs of Ireland.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09282</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">69648692</idno>
  <idno type="VID">184945</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240860626</idno>
  
            <idno type="OCLC"> 69648692</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing I341D</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R178600</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">69648692</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09282)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 184945)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2881:17)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Ireland. By the Commissioners of the Parliament of the Common-wealth of England for the Affairs of Ireland Whereas many persons, who have been in arms against the Parliament of the Common-wealth of England, and have of late come in upon articles, and submitted to the government of the said Common-wealth, and since their said submission ...</title>
                  <author>Ireland. Commissioners of the Common-wealth of England for the Affairs of Ireland.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>by VVill. Bladen,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno Dom. 1652.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title from caption and first lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Library Company of Philadelphia.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  History --  1649-1660 --  Sources.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660 --  Sources.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  Ireland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="declaration">
            <pb facs="tcp:184945:1"/>
            <head>IRE-<figure>
                  <figDesc>coat of arms of the Commonwealth of England, circa 1652</figDesc>
               </figure>LAND.</head>
            <head type="sub">By the Commissioners of the Parliament of the Common-wealth of ENGLAND <hi>for the Affairs of</hi> IRELAND.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas many persons, who have been in Arms against the Parliament of the Common-wealth of ENGLAND, and have of late come in upon Articles, and submitted to the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the said Common-wealth, and since their said Submission (under pretence of Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertie to travel into any of the parts of IRELAND about their private occasions) have again joined with such as continue in Hostilitie against the Parliament and their Forces, and thereby have found means to prolong the Warrs, and disturb the publick Peace: The said Commissioners of Parliament, upon Advice had and taken thereupon, at a Councel of War for the better prevention of the said evils for the future, Do Order and Declare, And it is hereby Ordered and Declared,</p>
            <p>First, That no person or persons who since the first of <hi>Ianuarie</hi> 1649. have been in Arms in IRELAND against the Parliament of the Common-wealth of ENGLAND shall tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vel or remove themselves out of the Counties wherein they are, or shall be licenced or permitted to live or inhabit in any other Countie without special Licence in writing first had and obtained from the Commander in Chief of the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments Forces in IRELAND, or from the Commander in Chief within the respective Precincts, wherein the said persons respectively inhabit, the said Licence in writing discribing the Age, Stature and colour of Hair of the person, with the oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>casion of his said travel or remove, and the time to be limited in his said Licence, how long to continue answerable to the occasion mentioned in the said Licence: (which said Licence is to be granted <hi>gratis</hi>) the said persons above mentioned, Travelling or Removing themselves as abovesaid, without such Licence as abovesaid, are to be judged and deemed as Spies; and to be proceeded against accordingly, as Spies and Enemies to the said Common-wealth.</p>
            <p>Secondly, That all persons who shall be found in Arms against the Parliament of the Common-wealth of ENGLAND, within the Provinces of <hi>Munster, Leinster, Connaught,</hi> and <hi>Ʋlster;</hi> at any time after the expiration of Ten days next en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>suing the Publication hereof, in every respective Precinct, shall be taken and proceeded against as Enemies, and shall suf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer accordingly.</p>
            <p>Thirdly, That all persons, who are included in any Treatie, for laying down of Arms, agreed upon at any time since the First of <hi>March</hi> 1651. And shall be found in Arms against the Parliament of the Common-wealth of ENGLAND, after the Twentieth day of <hi>Iuly</hi> instant, shall be proceeded against as Enemies and Traitors; and shall suffer accordingly.</p>
            <p>Fourthly, That all persons, who shall at any time after the expiration of Ten days next ensuing the Publication hereof in every respective Precinct, Harbour, Relieve, Assist, Comfort, Maintain or Abet any persons in Arms against the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the Common-wealth of ENGLAND or their Forces in IRELAND (except the persons so Harbouring or relieving be compelled thereunto by Force of Arms) shall be deemed and taken to be Enemies and Traitors to the said Common-wealth, and shall be proceeded against at the Court-Martial, as persons holding Correspondencie with, and giving Intelli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gence to the Enemie.</p>
            <p>And it is further Ordered, That the respective Commanders in Chief, in every respective Precinct in IRELAND, do cause due Publication to be made hereof in all Garrisons and Market-Towns within their several respective Limits, by beat of Drum, or sound of Trumpet: To the end all persons may have due Notice thereof.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Dated at <hi>Clonmell</hi>
                  <date>14. of <hi>Iuly,</hi> 1652.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Edm. Ludlow.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Miles Corbet.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Jo. Jones.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="license" subtype="order_to_print">
            <p>
               <hi>By the said Commissioners, It is Ordered that this Declaration be forthwith Printed and Published.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>IO. HUGHES.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>¶ Printed at DUBLIN, by WILL. BLADEN. <hi>Anno Dom.</hi> 1652.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:184945:2"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>